Mss.Ms.Coll.56
American Philosophical Society
- X. Meetings, Symposia, Workshops, 0.5 Linear feet 1 box
  - Salzburg Seminar [Austria], 1972-1974, 1983 (Box 32)
  - Sediment Transport by Wind and Water. 1989 (Box 32)
  - State of the Estuary Conference, 4th [San Francisco Estuary]. 1999, 1998-1999 (Box 32)
  - Symposium on Colorado River Ecology and Dam Managment. 1990 (Box 32)
  - Wisconsin Biodiversity Criteria Work-Session. 1994 (Box 32)
- XI. Field Notes, 1937-2006; 2.0 Linear feet 72 vols.
  Series XI comprises the field notebooks of Luna Leopold and a few other individuals with whom he worked. They are accompanied by two indices, hand-bound by Leopold, that list localities and dates for individual notebooks. The index for notebooks 1-70 does include listings for the volumes that are absent in this collection (see below).
  The enumerated series of books (as enumerated by Leopold) are uniform, standard field notebooks like those utilized by many outdoor professionals like geologists and surveyors. The notebooks are made of water-resistant materials and strongly bound for rough use. In addition to their use to record day-to-day collections of measurements and other field data, Leopold also used his notebooks to sometimes record personal information.
  Sequence of field notebooks as follows: Unnumbered vol. (January 1937) placed before enumerated Vol. 1 (April-June 1937). Vols. 1-39, 41-67, 69-71 (1937-2006) Vol. 40 (1968) lost by Leopold in 1968 (but see Nos. 39-41). Vol. 68 [1996-1997 in part] absent; not received by APS.
  Titles are quoted from spine titles as written by Leopold. Examinations of volumes, however, often indicate date ranges and other data that are in variance with Leopold's notations; these are indicated by alternate title listings inside square brackets.
  Many notebooks include attached fold-out items. Those that are still very strongly attached remain in place. Poorly attached and loose objects have been removed, their places indicated, and moved to box at end of series, "Small Items Removed from Field Notes". Place markers have been placed inside the notebooks; removed items are accompanied by original-location notations.
  - Index to Field Books [Nos. 1-70, 1937-2006], 1.0 vol. (Box 33)
  - Index to Field Books [Nos. 1-66, 1937-1991], 1937-1990; 1.0 vol. (Box 33)
  - [No number.] [1937 January 14-29; undated], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 1. "May-Sept 1937" [1937 April 21-June 24] "Field Notes--Upper Colorado", 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 2. "1938" [1937 October 2-1938 September 21; undated], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 3. "1938-1939 Oct 1938-July 1939" [1938 October 15-1939 July 4; undated], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 4. "1939-1940" [1939 January 9-1940 April 22], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 5. "1941 Rio Grande Cross-Sections 1941" [1941 May 16-June 20], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
    Leaves removed at end of volume (as received).
  - No. 6. "1940-1941 May 1940-Dec. 1941" [1940 May 4-1941 December 9], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 7. "1947-1948 Hawaii Apr-Oct. 1947" [1947 April 15-October 27], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
    "Book #10 notes taken out".
  - No. 8. "1942-1947 N.M., Calif. Hawaii 1942-Feb 1947" [1942 January 6-August 6; 1945 November 5-1947 April 1], 1942 January 6-1947 April 1; 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 9. "1947-1948 Hawaii Oct. 1947-July 1948" [1947 October 29-1948 July 28], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 10. "1948-1949 Hawaii Aug. 1948-Mar. 49" [1948 August 3-1949 March 29], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
    Printed map removed from between pp. 51/52: see Oversize Box 1, Folder 8. "Island of Maui, T.H. Rain Gages Operating 1948"; "COA & JC PRI & HSPA EXP. STA. MAR. 1948". No annotations.
  - No. 11. "1949-1950 Hawaii Gallup, N.M. Wyoming Mar. 1949-Aug. 1950" [1949 March 30-1950 July 19], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 12. "1950 Wyoming Aug.-Sept. 1950" [1949 December 15-1950 August 20; undated], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
    Rear leaves of notebook contain French and Spanish grammar lists.
  - No. 13. "1951 Wyoming Mar.-Aug. 1951" [1951 March 20-July 30], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
    Includes Leopold family genealogical notes.
  - No. 14. "1951-1952 Wyo., N. Mex. July 51-July 52" [1951July 30?-1952 July 26], circa 1951 July 30-1952 July 26]; 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 15. "1953 Maryland-Virginia Mar.-Aug. 1953" [1953 March 20-1955 May 19], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
    Graduated metal 6-inch rule (1/32-, 1/64-inch graduations) still inside home-made pocket inside rear cover.
  - No. 16. "1953 Wyoming July-Aug. 1953" [1953 May 9-August 18], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 17. "1952-1953 N. Mex.-Maryland Aug. 1952-Sept. '53" [1951 December 25-1953 December 14], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 18. "1954 Cal Tech Wyoming" [1953 December 26-1954 August 17; undated], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
    Fold-out map affixed to p. 20; no annotations.
  - No. 19. "1959 Colo., Wyo., Maryland May-Dec. 1955"; "June-Dec 1955" [1955 June 11?-December 29], circa 1955 June 11-December 29; 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 20. "1954-1955 Wyo. Md. Miss. 1954-1955" [1954 August 19-1955 February 22], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 21. "1955 India" [1955 March 14-17; undated], 1.0 vol. (Box 34)
  - No. 22. "1955 Maryland Feb.-May 1955" [1955 March 13-May 27], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
    N.B.: Five leaves with writing, between pp. 1-2, cut from book; pagination does not lapse. As received from Leopold.
  - No. 23. "1956 Maryland, Wyoming" [1956 January 10-July 10], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
    See also Oversize Box 1, Folder 8.
  - No. 24. "1956-1958" [1956 July 11-1958 May 1], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
    Indications on rear leaves that they once had held pressed plants, which now are absent (as received from Leopold).
  - No. 25. "1958 June-Aug. New Mexico" [1958 June 21-August 26], 1958 Jne 21-August 26; 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 26. "Marsh 1958 New Mex."; "August 1958 Marsh" [1958 August] [Arroyo Frijoles], circa 1958 August 18-28; 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 27. "1959 Maryland"; "Oct 1958" [1958 October 12-1959 June 2], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 28. "1959 Wyoming June 1959" [1959 June 9-15], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 29. "1959 Wyoming Myrick-Leopold" [Robert M. Myrick field notes, 1959 June 15-1960 August 14], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 30. "1959 Wyoming" [1959 June 18-1960 May 5], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 30A. "1959 J. P. Miller" [John P. Miller field notebook, 1959 July 4-25], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 30B. "1959-60 J. P. Miller" [John P. Miller field notebook, 1959 July 26-1960 August 24], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 30C. "1959" [Robert M. Myrick field notebook, 1959 October 7-1960 July 16], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 31. "1960-61 Maryland" [1960 August 5-1961 June 7], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
    Pages [135-139] comprise an itinerary of European travels, 1960 June 7-August 28.
  - No. 31A. "1961 Wiard Ranchos de Taos 1961" [L. A. Wiard field notebook, "Meander Study"], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
    Wiard title: "Rio Grande de Ranchos near Talpa, N. Mex. Meander Meadow downstream from gage Meander Study". Leopold annotations, 1981 October 21: "This book primarily w.s. cross profiles", "These cross profiles were made during the May or high flow observation period".
  - No. 31B. "1961 Wiard Ranchos de Taos 1961" [K. Medina, rodman's field notebook, "Meander Study", 1961 June 12], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
    Medina title: "Rio Grande de Ranchos near Talpa, N.Mex. Meander Study". Leopold annotation, 1983 February 4: "This book is the second survey, June 12, 1961, I believe to be water surface at each end of cross sections".
  - No. 31C. "1961" [Alan V. Jopling field notebook, Popo Agie River near Hudson, Wyoming, 1961 June 3, August 24], 1961 June 3, 1961 August 24; 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 32. "1961-1962 New Mex - Maryland [1961 June 19-1962 May 9], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 32A. "1961 J. P. Miller" [John P. Miller field notebook, 1961 March 31-July 18], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 32B. "1961" [Robert M. Myrick field notebook, 1961 July 6-17], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 33. "1962" [1962 May 18-July 11], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 34. "1962" [1962 July 28-1963 July 16], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 34A. "1962" [1962 May 29-June 2] [Wyoming], 1.0 vol. (Box 35)
  - No. 35. "1963" [1963 July 28-1964 May 30] (Box 36)
  - No. 35A. "1963 Detwyler"; "T. R. Detwyler, Field Book No. 1 June 27, 1963-Sept. 18, 1963", 1963 June 27-September 18 (Box 36)
  - No. 35B. "1963 Slaymaker" [H. Olav Slaymaker field notebook, 1963 June 15-September 6] (Box 36)
    Index to note book, pp. [156, 158].
  - No. 36. "1964" [1964 June 15-1965 February 13] (Box 36)
  - No. 37. "1965" [1964 September 2-1966 July 2] (Box 36)
    Includes song lyrics written during Colorado River expedition in Grand Canyon, Arizona.
  - No. 38. "1966" [1966 July 5-1967 June 19] (Box 36)
    Photo affixed facing p. 142, vertical downward view of pebbles, "Pole Cr. nr Sta D, 125 ft upstream from CL curve and on central gravel bar, June 20 67 p. 141 of LBL notebook. Provenance III".
  - No. 39. "1967" [1967 June 22-1968 November 26] (Box 36)
    Includes "Recipe de torillas por 19 torillas" [in English] and "David Thornburg's Sopapillas", pp. 53-54.
  - No. 40A. "1968 Sedim. Size East Fork" [Harvey Lozier Pfisterer field notebook, 1968 June 20-21, August 12-14] (Box 36)
    Leopold annotation: "LBL Book 40, Lost".
    June 20-21, Sediment sieve analyses. August 12-14, Continuation of profile down East Fork River.
  - No. 41. "1968" [1968 July 22-1969 August 12; undated] (Box 36)
    Leopold annotation: "Book 40 lost 1968".
    Includes "Snake R. aesthetics inventory", undated.
  - No. 41A. "Load & Size East Fork 1969 Book 1" [1969 May 5] (Box 36)
  - No. 41B. "Load & Size East Fork 1969 Book 2" [1969 June] (Box 36)
  - No. 42. "1969" [1969 May 24-1970 July 1] (Box 36)
    "Diary 1970" [1970 May 17-June 10], p. [148].
  - No. 43. "1970" [1970 March 21-1971 March 22] (Box 36)
    Leopold annotation, "Book 43 overlaps Book 42 March 1970-Mar 1971".
  - No. 44. "Bedload 1970"; "Bedload data and size analyses, East fork Project 1970" [1970 May 22-26] (Box 36)
  - No. 45. "World trip 1970-71" [1970 November 17-1971 February 14] (Box 36)
    Japan, New Zealand, Africa, Israel. Natural history notes include "Bird List--Africa Jan 1971", pp. 23-24.
  - No. 45A. "1971 Mike Dunn 1971 Lake Data" [Michael Dunn field notebook, 1971 March 18-May 20] (Box 36)
    "Note by Leopold. I hired Michael Dunn after seeing him handle a canoe on his family shooting preserve. The idea was for him to help me on Fremont Lake, Pinedale, Wyo, so he could help author a paper on lake ice breakup, for he wants to go into oceanography. He was to take my canoe out on the ice covered lake and get temperature profles to the lake bottom & observe the nature of the ice at breakup time. This book is his recorded observations. L.B.L."
  - No. 46. "1970-1972" [1970 July 13-1972 May 19] (Box 36)
  - No. 46A. "1972" [1967 October 8-1972 April 21] (Box 36)
    Notebook data for Watts Branch, Maryland, 1972 April 21. Notebook otherwise contains gasoline costs and mileages during period 1967 October 8-1972 March. Notebook also features home-made leather-strip pencil holder stapled to rear leaves.
  - No. 47. "1972-3 Bedload Cataract Watts Br." [1972 May 28-1973 June 6] (Box 36)
    Bedload project, Pinedale, Wyoming. Cataract Canyon, Utah. Watts Branch, Maryland. "1971 San Juan River trip itinerary", p. [151]. Includes throughout volume various pages with plans and notes for Leopold home in Pinedale, Wyoming.
  - No. 48. "1973" [1973 April 30-1975 February 3] (Box 37)
  - No. 49. "1974" [1974 March 20-July 29] (Box 37)
    In addition to domestic work includes foreign travel: "Israel", "Sinai Trip--gulf of Elat", "Galilee", and "Salzburg, Austria". Also includes notes pertaining to work on home in Pinedale, Wyoming, p. [153].
  - No. 50. "1974" [1974 July 31-1975 May 2] (Box 37)
  - No. 51. "1975" [1975 May 24-November 10] (Box 37)
    Includes song lyrics,"The Fox", relating to Berkeley geologists, pp. 142-143. Includes notes for "Pinedale Kitchen" (Leopold home in Wyoming), p. 149.
  - No. 52. "1975 1976" [1975 December 29-1977 January 2] (Box 37)
    Includes considerable special rain and streamflow data for "Faculty Club" and at Leopold home in Berkeley, California, 1977 January 1-2. Includes notes regarding work at Leopold home in Pinedale, Wyoming, p. [154].
  - No. 53. "1977" [1977 February 10-July 7] (Box 37)
  - No. 54. "1977 to July 78" [1977 July 14-1978 June 14] (Box 37)
    Includes: [1] "Survey of Nobles Land", pp. [144-145]. [2] Musical notation, p. [151]. [3] Notes for "LBL handmade bench at Cottonwood" [home in Pinedale, Wyoming], p. [152]. [4] Inside rear cover is a graph, "Time required to Read a Speech LBL."
  - No. 55. "1978-79" [1978 June 16-1979 November 29] (Box 37)
    Includes natural history notes relating to flowers, pp. 13-20; with fragments of pressed flowers, pp. 15/16, 17/18, removed to separate storage at end of series. Includes notes relating to work at Leopold home in Pinedale, Wyoming, p. [157].
  - No. 55A. "1978" [Field notebook of Carrie Nelson and L. B. Leopold], 1978 January 25; 1983 January 18; undated (Box 37)
    Begins with young child's [Nelson] natural history observations, undated, pp. [2-7]. Carrie Nelson is Luna Leopold's step-daughter. Luna Leopold field notes follow Nelson's notations, p. [8] ff: 1978 January 25, 1983 January 18, and undated field and general notes.
  - No. 56. "1980" [1980 January 11-September 1] (Box 37)
  - No. 57. "1980" [1980 June 21-August 14] (Box 37)
    Includes notes during conference in Wales on gravel-bed streams, 1980 June 21, pp. 2-8; and "Expense data--England June 19-July 2 '80" at end of notes. Includes "Hours worked by [step-daughter] Carrie [Nelson]"; and notes on Spanish grammar.
  - No. 58. "1980 Spain" [1980 September 22-October 7] (Box 37)
  - No. 59. "1980-81" [1980 October 31-1981 November 1] (Box 37)
  - No. 59A. "1980-81" [1980 August 2, 21; 1981 August 6-10] (Box 37)
    Data for Boulder Lake [Wyoming?]; and Marble Canyon-Grand Canyon, Arizona [notes for St. George, Utah, and Lees Ferry to Unkar Creek only]. Includes lyrics, "Colorado Saga No II" by "Luna and Barbara [Leopold] with help from Rod & Mary Anne".
  - No. 59B. [Lois I. Miller field notebook, "Barlow Braid, New Fork River nr. Cora, Wy", 1981 May 17-June 13] (Box 37)
  - No. 59C. "1981" [Lois I. Miller field notebook, "Barlow Braid, New Fork River", 1981 June 3-July 30] (Box 37)
  - No. 59D. "1981 3" [Bob O'Brian field notebook, 1981 June 10-14; 1984 April 22; 1985 March 21, April 4] (Box 37)
    Contents: Barlow Braid [New Fork River, Wyoming], 1981 June 10-14; Petaluma Marsh [Sonoma County, California], 1984 April 22; Strawberry Creek at Oxford Street [University of California at Berkeley], 1985 March 21; Arroyo Valle Creek [Alameda County, California], "Field trip for term paper", 1985 April 4.
  - No. 59E. "1981 Barlow Braid" [Barlow Braid, New Fork River, Wyoming, 1981 June 25-26; not Leopold] (Box 37)
    Nine small leaves, paginated 1-18, comprising section data, apparently not by Leopold. Originally in yellow plastic six-ring loose-leaf binder with spine labelled by Leopold (copy retained).
  - No. 60. "1981-82" [1981 June 28-1982 July 1] (Box 37)
    In addition to domestic data, includes "Travel to Sediment Conference Italy 1981", "Nairobi, Kenya", and "St. Andrews, Scotland". Includes "Itinerary Summer 1982" (May 16-June 28), p. 147; "Birds in Africa", pp. 150-132 [sic, 152]; "Itinerary & Diary", 1981 June 27-July 6, pp. 133-134 [sic, 153-154]. Information for last item dated "6/27/81" through "6/8" [in error, dates should continue with July].
  - No. 61. "1982-83 Israel & Wyo" [1982 July 2-1983 April 16] (Box 38)
    Includes data pertaining to Yuba River accident suit at which Leopold was an expert witness; see pp. 42-45. Israel trip begins with Itinerary, p. 69, to end of book; interjected, pp. 121-122 is itinerary in England.
  - No. 61A. "Petaluma Marsh" [Frank Lison field notes, 1984 March 17; P.G. Ngunjiri field notes, 1984 April 22; Anonymous(?) field notes, 1984 November 24], 1984 March 17, April 22, November 24 (Box 38)
    Written on tape on front of volume: "Leopold C D-M 3/17".
  - No. 62. "1983 84" [1983 June 20-1984 November 17] (Box 38)
    Includes "Notes on deposition behind dams, Jerusalem, June 20 1983", pp. 1-2.
  - No. 63. "1984-85" [1984 May 16-1985 August 22] (Box 38)
    Includes trip to Greece, pp. 2-17; "Bird list Greece", p. [154].
  - No. 63A. "Braided Channels--Wyoming 1984 1" [1980 August 21; 1984 July 24-28. Not Leopold] (Box 38)
    Volume includes "Boulder Lake [Wyoming] Bathymetric Study", 1980 August 21, pp. 2-5. Notes in this volume not by Leopold.
  - No. 63B. "Braided Channels--Wyoming 1984 2" [Peter Whiting field notebook, 1984 June 18-July 10] (Box 38)
  - No. 63C. "Braided Channels--Wyoming 1984 3" [Peter Whiting field notebook, 1984 June 26-July 16] (Box 38)
  - No. 63D. "Braided Channels--Wyoming 1984 4" [Peter Whiting field notebook, 1984 June 7-July 2] (Box 38)
  - No. 63E. "Braided Channel 1985 12" [Don Friend field notebook, 1985 May 21-June 12] (Box 38)
    On front flyleaf verso is written, "D.F./Book #2". Includes "M.A. ideas", p. 149.
  - No. 63F. "11" [Carol Scott field notebook, 1985 April 5-1986 January 21] (Box 38)
  - No. 64. "1985-1989" [1985 September 17-1989 June 6] (Box 38)
  - No. 64A. "Pole Cr. Collins 1986" [Collins field notebook, 1986 June 21-27] (Box 38)
    Pages 140-149 comprise a calendar of work and billing expenses relating to Leopold's Federal Court deposition in Colorado as an expert witness.
  - No. 64B. "Field notes re Justice", "Pole Cr. Collins" [Collins field notebook, 1986 June 21-27; Leopold (Colorado), 1989 June 1-2], 1986 June 21-27; 1989 June 1-2 (Box 38)
  - No. 65. "1990" [1988 October 30; 1989 June 23-1990 July 26] (Box 38)
    Includes: [1] "Work summary for Justice Dept", pp. [152-155]. [2] "USGS at the Hearings", p. 39 [Congressional hearings on U.S. Geological Survey activities.] [3] "Leopold Presidential Address"; poem, Geological Society of America Annual Meeting, Minneapolis. [4] Original lyrics, "Colorado Saga June 1965" [from Colorado River trip in Grand Canyon], pp. 4-7. [5] Original lyrics, "Desolation Canyon" by "LBL [and] ACL", pp. 50-51. [6]Lyrics and guitar notations for Spanish songs,pp. 2, 8-29, 46-47; and for English songs, pp. 30-38, 42-45, 48-49 [paginations differ from those given in index]. [7] Notation for guitar, "Bruce [Leopold] on double thumbing", p. [158].
  - No. 66. "1990-1994" [1990 August 26-1994 May 23] (Box 38)
    Pages 147-148 include personal notes.
  - No. 67. "1994-1996" [1994 July 12-1996 January 25]
    "Begin April 1994" but first entry, immediately afterward, is 1994 July 12. Notation at end of field entries, p. [118]: "See Book 68 1996"; but Book 68 is absent. This notebook also includes numerous pages of personal notations.
    [Notebook no. 68 is absent; not received by APS.]
  - No. 69. "'97-2000" [1997 August 17-2000 May 31, 2002 June 4]
    First leaf notes "Aug 1997-May 2000"; book includes one additional notation regarding personal legal suit dated Tuesday, June 4, 2002 and "See book 70".
  - No. 70. "2000" [2000 May 31-2006 January 18] (Box 38)
    Last field data in 2001. Remainder of volume composed chiefly of calendarical and personal notes; an extension of Leopold's "Journal" series.
  - No. 71. "2006" [2006 January 21-February 22] (Box 38)
    Contents comprise calendarical and personal notes.
  - Small Items Removed From Field Notes, 1.0 box (Box 39)
    Many Field Notes volumes include attached fold-out items. Poorly attached and loose objects have been removed, their places indicated, and moved to this box. Place markers have been placed inside the notebooks; removed items are accompanied by original-location notations.
    Items have been removed and placed here from Vols. 28, 37-39, 41B, 43, 46, 46A, 47-50, 55, 58, 59, 61, 63, 63B, 64-66, 70.
- XII. Journal, 1922; 1931-2003; undated; 3.0 Linear feet 12 vols.
  Series XII comprises Leopold's personal Journals, 1931-2003 (with a 1922 boyhood list of birds). Eleven volumes are hand-bound by Leopold; a twelfth volume in progress is held between cloth covers on loose-leaf posts, and the contents of a large envelope attached inside the rear cover that have now been removed to separate folders. The Journals tell Leopold's personal stories, work perspectives, and travelogues, although the last two volumes of his "Field Notes" (Series XI) also served to document some of his personal activities and thoughts from 2001 to the day before his death in 2006. The Journals are profusely illustrated with photographs and some hand-drawn sketches; even the occasional water-color painting. Extensive handwritten and typewritten texts detail adventures, observations, concerns, and ideas. The earliest of Leopold's Journals delightfully record an observant naturalist’s eye, salting his pages with careful drawings of birds, and laying between the leaves of the book pressed plants and bird feathers. He dabbled in poetry, some of which appears in his Journals and Field Notes, as well as an unpublished small collection that he assembled in the 1990s. His Journals and Field Notes also contain diversions of musical lyrics (some of them original) and musical notations, usually for guitar.
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold Volume 1 1931-35", 1922; 1931-1935 November 3; 1.0 vol. (Box 40)
    Begins with Luna Leopold list of birds, 1922.
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold Volume 2 1935-40", 1935 November 8-1940 September 29; 1.0 vol. (Box 40)
    Original Watercolors: "Das Jagdschloss"; "Ozarks 1939" [ornamental title].
    Of Note: "Delineacíones y Especificacíones por El Ranchito del ’Horcado la casa de Srs. Luna y Starker Leopold Santa Fé, Nuevo Mexico" [designs for a house; elevations and floor plans, details, bills of materials].
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold [Volume 3] 1940-1946", 1940 October-1946 March 13; 1.0 vol. (Box 41)
    Of note: "Letters to Bruce [Leopold]", when Bruce was a baby.
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold [Volume 4] 1946-1949", 1946 November 29-1948 June 28; [1949]; 1.0 vol. (Box 41)
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold Volume 5 1950-56", 1949 November-1956 March 22; 1.0 vol. (Box 42)
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold Volume 6 1956-61", 1956 June 29-[1961]; 1.0 vol. (Box 42)
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold Volume 7 1962-66", 1951; 1961 July; 1962 Spring-1966 December; 1.0 vol. (Box 43)
    Title-page indicates, "Volume 7 1962-67".
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold Volume 8 1967-77", circa 1910; 1911; 1918; 1965 June-1977; 1.0 vol. (Box 43)
    Title-page indicates, "1966-1977".
    Frontispiece, 8x10 photo, "Supervisory force, Carson National Forest in Tres Piedras, New Mexico, forest supervisor's headquarters--1911. Left to right-- Aldo Leopold, Dep. Forest Supervisor Ira T. Yarnall, Forest Assistant C.C. Hall, Forest Supervisor Photo by R.E. Marsh 1911".
    Additional photos of note: [1] "My father, Aldo Leopold, near Springerville, Arizona, about 1910". [2] "Starker [Leopold] and Sonny Jim [dog] Mother's ranch, 1918". [3] "The Ranch, 1918" (children and woman with hay wagon).
    Other items of note: [1] Bird-banding records in Washington, DC, 1953-1956. [2] "Notes on Wine 1959" [-1960].
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold Volume 9 1979-82", circa 1935-1978; bulk 1977 May 20-1982; 1.0 vol. (Box 44)
    Includes section, "Some earlier but important history"; circa 1935-1978. And in this section also correspondence from "Christine", 1959, undated; and from Mrs. Kirk Bryan, 1964.
    Section, "Poems, some early"; 1938 February, undated.
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold Volume 10 1983-91", 1986-1991; 1.0 vol. (Box 44)
  - "The Journal of Luna B. Leopold Volume 11 1992-99", 1992 April 3-1998; 1.0 vol. (Box 45)
    Pocket inside rear cover contains printed materials predating 1992.
  - [Journal, Volume 12], 1997 March 27-2003 September 20; 1.0 vol. (Box 45)